viff.org 2015-12-06

# Privacy Policy | Vancouver International Film Festival

## **How the Greater Vancouver International Film Festival Society's Policy Protects Your Privacy**

The Greater Vancouver International Film Festival Society (VIFF) is strongly committed to being a leader and innovator in the film and television industries just as it is committed to protecting the personal information you provide when you buy tickets/passes to any of the Vancouver International Film Festival screenings and related events; Vancity Theatre screenings; attend a VIFF Industry Conference session, tête-à-tête or speed dating meeting, master class, or workshop; subscribe to VIFF's various newsletters; or make a donation.

VIFF is a membership-based organization. This means that we must collect personal information from those who want to become members. We also collect personal information from friends of the organization, including newsletter subscribers, volunteers, and others. As a registered charity, we are required by the Canada Revenue Agency to collect personal information from donors.

* * *

## **Collection, Use, and Disclosure**

## Collection

The personal information that you voluntarily provide to the Greater Vancouver International Film Festival Society is protected under the provisions of British Columbia’s _Personal Information Protection Act_. Depending on the nature of the transaction, VIFF generally collects, your name, address (post and electronic), telephone number and payment information related to ticket purchases, passes and package purchases, donations, newsletters and information mailings. The Greater Vancouver International Film Festival Society may collect demographic information such as your date of birth, gender and language preference for marketing and fundraising purposes. 

## Use

As a patron of VIFF, you can enjoy some of the following benefits:

  * attend screenings of world-class cinema,
  * participate in an VIFF Industry session, or
  * attend a Festival, Vancity Theatre, or VIFF Industry related special event.

As a donor of VIFF, you can enjoy some of the following additional benefits:

  * savings on regular ticket prices,
  * seating priority,
  * discounts, or
  * front of line purchasing opportunities.

In order to provide you with these special offers and other advantages, we use your information to:

  * email your tickets;
  * respond to your inquiries;
  * provide you with access to your on-line account;
  * inform you of important changes to VIFF screenings;
  * provide you with our newsletters and brochures;
  * conduct financial transactions;
  * administer contests and promotions;
  * notify you of special events and screenings;
  * solicit financial support and ticket purchases;
  * thank donors and issue tax receipts;
  * invite donors and sponsors to special events and functions;
  * provide assistance with ticket purchases;
  * provide donors with our newsletters and stewardship reports regarding their gift;
  * provide recognition in print materials;
  * solicit donations;
  * generate statistics.

## Disclosure

Your personal information is not shared, rented, exchanged or otherwise disclosed to any outside third party except where authorized and or required by law.

The Greater Vancouver International Film Festival Society uses external services and suppliers to assist it in various functions such as processing ticket transactions.  Through agreements with these partners and their commitment to protect your privacy, please know that your information is managed with the same level of sensitivity as we do. A confidentiality clause that describes what type of information is being shared and for what purpose is incorporated in the contracts.

* * *

## **Standard Internet Usage Information Automatically Collected**

Software programs are used to monitor network traffic and to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information, or otherwise cause damage. When you visit VIFF website, these software programs automatically receive and temporarily store information supplied by your browser (for example, browser type and operating system) in our webserver logs. Some of the information automatically collected by our servers when you browse our website includes:

  * the network location and the Internet Protocol (IP) address of the computer you used to contact VIFF website;
  * the name of the domain you used to access the Internet (.com, .org, .net, .ca, etc.);
  * the type of browser you used;
  * the type of operating system you used (Windows, Mac OS, iOS, Android, etc.);
  * the date and time you accessed the site;
  * the pages you have accessed and the documents you have downloaded; and
  * the Internet address of the website from which you linked directly to our site, if applicable.

In most circumstances, this is anonymous statistical data and VIFF makes no attempt to link this data, nor the IP addresses of the computers that have contacted our website, with the identity of individuals visiting our site unless an attempt to damage the site has been detected. The programs are never used to gather specific personal information such as your name, your phone number or your e-mail address.

Specifically, VIFF also uses information obtained through technology in the following ways:

  * Determine whether VIFF website visitors are correctly accessing online content and programs;
  * Measure the effectiveness of VIFF marketing campaigns by tracking the regional location of Web visitors (down to the level of city boundaries only) and information such as “click-through” and movement within VIFF website;
  * Conduct year-over-year market research analysis of VIFF Web visitor engagement and online buying patterns and trends from one programming season to the next in order to attract more audience members to VIFF; and
  * Determine the types of devices used by VIFF Web visitors and tailor content to their platforms.

## Cookies

Cookies are used to track how our visitors use this site, to determine sites previously visited or to facilitate the use of secure portions of this site. A cookie is a file that may be placed on your hard drive without your knowledge by a website to monitor your use of the site. The cookies we use do not allow us to identify individuals. They are compiled into statistical information on traffic patterns and are used to assess and improve the efficiency of the site.

We use two types of cookies:

  * Session cookies - These are used as an integral part of the identification process for some of our online applications. This is for security purposes to determine that you are who you say you are and to provide you with your confidential account information during an online session. No personal information is kept in session cookies and they are stored only in your browser's temporary (cache) memory. When you log out of your session, the cookie is no longer valid and is discarded when you close your browser.
  * Persistent cookies - These are more permanent and can be re-read when you return to the site that placed them on your computer. The information in them is written onto your hard drive and remains there until the expiry date of the cookie. They are used to identify and provide personalized features (for example, to help us remember items in your shopping cart) and for tracking traffic patterns to and from our site. For more information on the tracking we use, refer to the Google Analytics section below.

## Google Analytics

Google Analytics, a Web analytics service provided by Google Inc., helps to measure traffic patterns to, from, and within our public websites. This analytics measurement tool uses "session" and "persistent" cookies to collect standard Internet log information and to track visitor behaviour information in an anonymous form. Persistent cookies are stored on your computer and expire two years after your last visit to our websites. The information generated by the cookies about your use of the website (including your IP address, truncated to ensure your anonymity) is transmitted to Google. No personal, identifying information is recorded or provided to Google. This anonymous information is then used to evaluate visitors' use of the website and to compile statistical reports on Canada Site activity. The aggregate data and statistical reports are used only to help us make our site more useful to visitors and are made available only to Web managers and other designated staff who require this information to perform their duties.

For further information about Google Analytics, please refer to [Google Analytics Privacy Policy](http://www.google.com/intl/en_ALL/privacy/privacy-policy.html).

If you wish, you may opt out of being tracked by Google Analytics by disabling or refusing the cookies; by disabling JavaScript within your browser; or by using the [Google Analytics Opt-Out Browser Add-On](http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en). Disabling Google Analytics or JavaScript will still permit you to access comparable information or services from our websites. However, if you disable your session cookie option, you will still be able to access our public website, but you might have difficulties accessing any secure services.

If you have never disabled the session cookie option, it should be enabled by default. To disable cookies or JavaScript, please refer to your vendor's browser instruction guide.

Please note that this website provides links to other sites that are not covered by this privacy policy.

* * *

## **Your Choice - Your Rights**

We are compliant with Canada’s Anti-Spam Legislation (CASL). Commercial Electronic Messages which are sent by VIFF will be sent in accordance with the provisions of that legislation. If you are a subscriber to any of VIFF’s mailing lists, you may click on the link included at the bottom of every electronic message we send to manage your subscriptions.

If at any time you would like to access, correct or add to your personal information that we maintain, make a complaint regarding the management of your personal information or regarding our compliance with CASL, or be removed from any of our mailing or call centre lists for any of VIFF services, we encourage you to contact the Privacy Officer, at [privacy@VIFF.org](mailto:privacy@VIFF.org), at the Greater Vancouver International Film Festival Society, who will address your concerns, complaints, and questions.

Mailing address: 1181 Seymour Street, Vancouver BC  V6B 3M7  
Telephone: 604.685.0260, ext. 998   
Facsimile: 604.688.8221

For more information concerning your rights under the [_Personal Information Protection Act_](http://www.bclaws.ca/Recon/document/ID/freeside/00_03063_01), or if you are dissatisfied with a response you receive from our Privacy Officer regarding a privacy concern with this website, please contact the Office of the Information and Privacy Commissioner
